A Guide to the Ruiz Case Office of Special Master Records, 1979-1992.
Ruiz Case Office of Special Master Records,
1979-1992.
Special Master, Office of
222 ft.
Dolph Briscoe Center for American History, The University of Texas at Austin
Records relate to the work of the Office of the Special Master, created to oversee compliance with and implementation of the rulings of the federal courts in the landmark case of Ruiz et al. v. State of Texas.
Access Restrictions
Some restrictions apply. Contact repository for further information.
Scope and Contents
Correspondence, pleadings, exhibits, motions, reports, orders, plans, and official publications relate to the work of the Office of the Special Master, created to oversee compliance with and implementation of the rulings of the federal courts in the landmark case of Ruiz et al. v. State of Texas. Also included are trial transcripts and exhibits in the Ruiz case from the law office of attorney William Bennett Turner, as well as a large body of prison medical testimony.
Index Terms
Estelle, W. J.; Ruiz, David.; Turner, William Bennett.; Texas. Dept. of Corrections.; Prison reformers--Texas.; Prisoners--Legal status, laws, etc.--Texas.; Prisoners--Medical care--Texas.; Prisoners--Texas.; Prisons--Texas.
Detailed Description of the Records
- Tyler Division files: (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Connor, James W., TY 75-21-CA (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Log #08-0086, TY 75-229, Eddie Smith vs. Texas Board of Pardons and Paroles and Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Chivers, Charles vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Brewer, E. J. vs. Wardens (TDC) (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Thomas, Edger vs. Office Womble, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Arnold, K. vs. O. S. Savage (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Gurson vs. Putska (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Easter, Wilmer Lane vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Ledford vs. Estelle (A) (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Shelby, Thomas E. vs. Turner (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Ledford vs. Estelle (B) (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Armstrong, Rayford vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Robert Earl Robertson vs., Estelle et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Rudd, Rolend vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Chaddock, Danny Ray vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Young vs. TDC (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - McNeely, Curtis (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Amoshee Jones vs. Charles Berny (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Walker, Wilson (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Harold L. Grant vs. H. Garner (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Crawford III, Johnny vs. Cousins (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Calvin, Denny Lee vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Portley, Jerry D. vs. L. C. Daniels (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Calvin, Danny Lee vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Velez, George vs. Lt. Johnson (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Lacey, Antonio M. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Odom, Donald E. vs. Jordan (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Williams, Alvin E. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Reese, Alvin R. vs. Paul W. Duff (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Ronald J. Holleman vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Allums, Joe David vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Brown, James Taylor vs. G. Ferguson (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Malbrue, L. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Sanford, W. C. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Plemons, James W. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Webb, William Edward vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Seifullah, Muhhamed A. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Fulbright, Charles vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Eubanks, Wesley (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Small, Carl E. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Lacey, ANtonio (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Muhamud Seifullah aka James Powell vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Reyna, F. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Sosa, Samuel G. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - John F. Leinweber vs. T. D. White (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Salazar, Marianno R. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Coleman, Tony J. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Johnson, Paul R. vs. TDC (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - McGrew, James vs. Ralph Gray (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hernandez, R. O. vs. Cousins (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Ned vs. Estelle and White (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Toledo, Richard R. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Jonathan Goff vs. Carl D. White (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Pedro Garza vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Bonner, Jr. N. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Dehn, Keith A. vs. T. L. Austin (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Horace, Isom (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Beasley, William D. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hinton, William G. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hill, Jimmie G. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Thompson, Joe M. vs. Capt. Duff (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Culbert, Harold vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Thompson, Joe Nathan vs. Warden White (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Aldridge, Rulford G. vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Szczeck, John G. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Walker, K. E. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - McDade, William J. vs. C. T. White (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Cranford, Kenneth Eugene vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Wells, Leroy vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Leinweber, John F. vs Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Crick, William J. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Lawford, Virgil G. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Burney, Alfred E. vs. Dr. Jordan (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Mallet, Michael D. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Pickle, David vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Flowers, Larry C. et. al. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Williams, Charles vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Simms, E. W. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Lovell, Rodney G. vs. Cousins, R. M. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Holts, Larry vs. Turner, Ed (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Plemons, James William (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Easter, Wilmer L. vs Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Powell, James Lee vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Flowers, Larry Charles vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Marshall, James V. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Smith, Rodney Wayne (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hayes, Michael Joe vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Johnson, Eddie (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Montes, Andres G. vs. TDC (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Brown, David W. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hayes, Michael J. vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Johnson, Michael vs. A. J. Mossakowski (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Morrison, Rex Elwin vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Lambright, Luther vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Freeman, Anthony (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Johnston, Randall (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Sawyer, Thomas C. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Parnell, Jimmy Lee vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Pearson, Jerry L. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Williams, Charles vs. Harris (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hayes, Michael J. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Manzer, Juan (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Matthews, Marcus (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Sawyer, Thomas (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hurley, Fredd W. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Harvey, Donny J. vs. Warden Cousins (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - McMihelk, Gene K. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Riddle, Michael (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Riddle, Michael E. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Lambright, Luther vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Berrie, Tommy vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Johnson, Paul R. vs. TDC (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Arnold, Richard Glenn vs. Pittock (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Gavitt, Raymond Lee vs. Jordan (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Caraway, Lee Dale (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Faurie, Steve vs. W. J. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Frazier, Eddie vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Grooms, David vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Guerrero, Dan G. vs. R. Putska, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hinton, William G. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Parks, Wade Roy vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hammond, Louis F. vs. Jordan (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Lattimer, Anthony vs. TDC, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Jones, Ricky Laurr (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - McGuire, Curtis (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Parnell, Jimmy vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Brown, ALvin R. vs. Capt. Wood (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Campbell, Jr., M. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Randolph, Henry (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Whalon, John vs. Fry (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Moss, Johnny W. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Jordan, Samuel (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Randolph, Henry W. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Sportsman, William (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Long, William G. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Randolph, Henry (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Masengale, Lewis (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Brewer, E. J. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hobbs, Johnny (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Beasley, Bobby Lee vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Ross, Dirk (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Butler, James H. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Flanagan, Gilbert vs. D. U. McKaskle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Carroll, Clifford vs. Mark White (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hardin, James R. vs. Henry and McCoy (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Bann, Richard L. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Gill, et. al. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Baker, Tony A. vs. White, Assistant Warden (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Cole, Jr., Paul Franklin vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Ford, David W. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Brown, Randolph vs. Board of Classification (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Finney, H. R. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Carroll, Clifford D. vs. Herklotz (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Garner, Early vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Dempsey, Melvin Russell vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Kohler, Edward A. vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hernandez, M. J. vs. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hardgrove, Michael vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Davis, Herman E. vs. vs. D. J. Poppell (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Taylor, Richard W. vs. J. D. Phillips (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Cooper, Steven Paul vs. Dr. Jordan (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Hamilton, Steven D. vs. Bureau, TDC, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
  - Carter, Jr., Richard J. vs. Dan McKaskle, et. al. (Box 93-458/1 (05272722))
- Orders, 1987-1990, 1992 (Box 94-458/2 (05272314))
- Inmate pleadings and orders, 1989-1990, 1992 (Box 94-458/2 (05272314))
- Guillermo Gomez, et. al. vs. George Waldron, et. al. (Box 94-458/3 (05272336))
- Magee prisoner correspondence, March-December 1989, January-May, 1990 (Box 94-458/3 (05272336))
- Fiscal correspondence, OSM, 1983-1991 (Box 94-458/3 (05272336))
- Comprehensive health care plan, annual report, April 1988 - March 1989 (Box 94-458/4 (05272303))
- Inmates pleadings and orders, 1988, July-December, 1989 (Box 94-458/4 (05272303))
- Texas Department of Corrections, Occupational Safety and Health Manual, 1989 (Box 94-458/4 (05272303))
- Report of the office of the Special Master on TDCs, revised Occupational Safety and Health Manual, 1989 (Box 94-458/4 (05272303))
- TDCs Manual of Policies and Procedures for Health Care, 1985 (Box 94-458/4 (05272303))
- Ruiz file index, Vol. II (Box 94-458/4 (05272303))
- State of Texas Jail Standards, 1988 (Box 94-458/4 (05272303))
- Corrections Corporation of America and Wackenhut Corrections Corporation (Box 94-458/5 (05272391))
- Wackenhut Services (Box 94-458/5 (05272391))
- Special masters, compliance reports, topical listings (Box 94-458/5 (05272391))
- Exhibits 1-36 (Box 94-458/5 (05272391))
- Annual report, April 1, 1988 - March 31, 1989 (Box 94-458/5 (05272391))
- TDC Comprehensive Health Care Plan, November 1984 (Box 94-458/5 (05272391))
- Various health care plans, 1987 (Box 94-458/5 (05272391))
- Ruiz defendant reports, 1989-1990: (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - First annual report, necessity allowance (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Notice concerning visitation (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Report, dorm renovations (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Second semi-annual report (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Second report, access to courts, counsel and public officials (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - First annual report, crowding (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Second annual report, support services (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Report, dorm rennovations, 1984 (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Compliance report on Hobby Unit (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Report, Daniel Unit (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Notice concerning visitation (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Hobby Unit health care services (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
  - Trusty comp. assessment (Box 94-458/6 (05274874))
- Galveston Division: (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - L. R. Stansbury vs. J. B. Kline (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Billy R. Hudson vs. Capt. Lunsford (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Gray, John R. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Stephen J. Roliard vs. Brazoria (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Donny Joel Harvey vs. Unknown Sheriff (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Charles Stapleton vs. C. R. Martin (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Oss Smith, Jr. vs. Lt. Davidson (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Oss Smith vs. David Christian (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Donny J. Harvey vs. Maj. Gilliam (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Albert Aranda vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Cook, Larry W. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Brown, Carl vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - White, Charlie C. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Hawkins, Henry vs. Capt. Turner (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Davis, C. Clinton vs. C. Rivera (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - James, Terry Ray vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Gordon, Robert W. vs. Don V. D. O. A. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Haas, Chester V. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Dillard, Terry vs. Charles McAndrews (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Bennie Lee Gill, Jr. vs. E. O. Carranea (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Smith, Oss vs. Hernandez, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Daniels, Clifton G. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Joseph, J. D. vs. W. J. Estelle, Jr. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Harvey, Donny J. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Davis, Johnny O. vs. L. Sharrod, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Dorsey, Nathaniel F. vs. Joe M. Taylor (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Smith, Oss Jr. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Jackson, Willie vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Johnnie, Tasby, et. al. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Scribner, Allyn vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Schneider, Michael E. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Mitchell, Maurice (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Pussey, John (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Bradley, Ivory Lee vs. L. Hunt and Carranza (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Evans, B. S. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Smith, M. V. vs. Yeager, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Fulbright, C. R. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Pussey, John vs. W. B. Hagans, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Amos, David Lee (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Ynostrosa, Fernando (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Williams, Samuel E. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Bradley, Ivory (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Williams, William C. vs. B. K. Fleming (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Joseph, Julius D. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Milton, Willie Arthur (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Haas, Chester V. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Harris, Samuel, Jr. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Pussey, John (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Williams, Wilbert C. vs. Sanchez (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Jones, Leslie L. vs. Moya, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Sanchez, James G. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Lopez, Jose (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - McAdams, John (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Anastasiades, Anthony (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Turner, Jimmy E. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Felix, James (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Harris, Samuel vs. George Delgado et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Gozman, Ulvado (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Frank, Donald Ray (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Tiller, William C. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Gordon, Robert W. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Smith, Oss, Jr. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Kyles, Richard D. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Dykes, J. W. vs. Whitworth, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Price, Joe vs. N. K. Ramsey (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Nycum, Michael (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Webb, William Edward vs. Pedro Soto, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Pussey, John, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Pussey, John vs. A. H. Valesquez (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Reed, James C. vs. L. D. Hunt (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Jones, Charles (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Vasquez, Johnny (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Cervantes, F. vs. TDC, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Muhhamad, Allah S. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Curtis, Ronnie (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Walls, Alton vs. M. W. Moore, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Calloway, Carl Lee (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Guilbeaux, Gerald P. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Norman, Louis James (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Totton, Roger (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Arnold V. McLure (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Lasha, James B. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Carmouche, Hubert (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Brewer, Gary E. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Arnold, Pete (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Smith, Donald Ray (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Young, Charles Ray vs. Ray Procunier (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Worley and Lester vs. Moore (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Totten, Roger Lee (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Thomas, Ernest M. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Robinson, David R. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Hubbard, Mel R. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Clemons, Jimmy (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Burns vs. Dearing (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Jones, Charles (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Hall, Stanley (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Washington, Willie (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Cook, Larry W. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Flores, Fernando (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Norman, Louis J. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Rohlfing, Michael (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Arnold, Pete (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Brent, Gary (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Holloway, L. D. vs. R. K. Procunier (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Brooks, William G. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Norman, Louis J. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Brewer, Gary E. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Totton, Roger L. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Moore, Ray F. vs. Procunier, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Kates, David E. vs. Procunier, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Milton, William A. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Guillory, Lee R. vs. Procunier, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Whitely, Clarence (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Davis, Arthur J. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Arnold, Pete (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Plyant, Ronald C. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Canada, Roger (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Brewer, Gary E. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Arnold, Pete (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Banils, Gayle L. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Porter, Charles (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Starkey, David (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Mills, Michael W. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Muhhammad, Elisha S. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Howard, THomas D. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Muhhammad, Rudd (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Muhhammad, Elisha S. vs. Terrell, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Loya, Louis (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Jimmy Appleman (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Jackson, Willie James (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Michael G. Williams (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Muhhammad, Elisha Rudd (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Breazeale, Thomas (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Smith, Michael D. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Young, Charles Ray (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
- Houston Division: (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Enriquez, Juan vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Hill, Raymond W. vs. Coffield (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Hilliard vs. J. Anderson (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Rollins, Jacob vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - McDuffie, Huey P. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Davis, Ronald L. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - David Moya vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Willie J. Jackson vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Williams, Israel vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Raobert L. Hague vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Anthony Zilka vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Muhamud A. Seifullah vs. F. Hofheinz (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Dale M. Hart vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Perry Wright vs. TDC (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Reginald Wright vs. McLeon (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Al. Hernandez vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Simon, Lloyd A. vs. Cousins (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Alvin Sheppard vs. Houston City Police Department (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Paul Rougeau vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Martinez, Jose J. vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Draymon, Jenkins vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Shebazz vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Morocco, J. J. vs. Johnson, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Samuel Jackson vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Waffer, Samuel T. vs. TDC, W. J. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Lantrid, William T. vs. Macmillan (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Nelson, J. vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Bobby Roberts vs. Dupnik, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Fobbs, Ulysses C. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Bobby J. Roberts vs. Billy R. Ware (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Raymundo R. Mendoza vs. Jenkins, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Anders, Glenn S. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Tepp, Steve G. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Elmer G. Walker vs. Sheriff Heard (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Winn, II, Robert Lee vs. J. A. William Don [sic], et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Shaw, Robert vs. W. J. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Johnson vs. McKaskle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Davis, S. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Freeman, A. R. vs. Gipson, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Carl White vs. Jack Heard, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Beaudoy, Charles vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - John M. Wilson vs. Ray Hardy, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Samuel James Jackson vs. Williamson (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Harvey, Donny J. vs. Estelle (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
  - Muller, Jerry vs. Estelle, et. al. (Box 94/458/7 (05274863))
- Objections filed by plaintiff class members concerning stipulations concerning law libraries, notary services and future prisons (Box 94-458/8 (05272755))
- Damon Downs, transfer to Rusk (Box 94-458/8 (05272755))
- Lamar vs. Coffield orders, race discrimination (Box 94-458/8 (05272755))
- L. D. Hilliard (Box 94-458/8 (05272755))
- Good time credits for Ruiz witnesses, Brown vs. Garwry (Box 94-458/8 (05272755))
- Richard S. Ortiz, pleadings (Box 94-458/8 (05272755))
- Clippings (Box 94-458/8 (05272755))